EIKICHI - AZUSA ONIZUKA
To my dearest wife.
It's been two weeks since
you went back to your parents' home.
Has anything changed with you since then?
DIVORCE FORM
As for me,
one of my students
tried to start a new team…
It was only a short time,
but thank you for everything.
Don't try to reset
the hard work you put in so far.
I barely managed to stop her
from quitting school.
And as a result,
I got one more good rating
in the feedback system.
-How about it?
-Please!
We haven't gotten new members yet,
but I'll do my best
not to lose to the two of them.
So can you come home soon,
so we can do drills together?
Oh, right.
"What makes a Great Teacher?"
To answer the homework you gave me…
-It's fun!
-It's very, very interesting!
-Why not join us?
-How about it?
Our Drill Team is recruiting!
It must be a teacher who never gives up
until the very end, and who thinks
about what is best for the students.
I think that is the answer.
I think this should work.
WHAT AN OBVIOUS ANSWER
DON'T SAY IT SO PROUDLY
Good morning.
Hmm?
Wait a minute, just now,
you responded to
Ms. Kashiwabara's "good morning,"
but ignored my "good morning," right?
That's not true.
Right?
You're just imagining it.
Well, if you say so.
All 28 of you are here today,
so if you ever have any problems like
Ken-Ken and Yuukichi did, tell me.
If there's anything I can do,
I'll do whatever it takes.
Heck, you can even call me
"Great Teacher" if you want.
Mr. Onizuka.
What is it?
Maybe Ms. Kashiwabara also
has some passionate words to share?
No. I just thought
I should hand these out.
Please go ahead.
My next class
will have you work in pairs,
so please check them.
I'm with you, Yuukichi?
Hey! That's my line.
Ms. Ishibashi.
Nice to work with you.
Yeah. Likewise.
I took your wishes into consideration,
so it should be fine,
but if there's any issue, do tell me.
Okay, thanks.
I'm kind of jealous.
When I was in high school,
we didn't have classes
where students joined forces
and gave it their all.
It's nothing so frivolous.
The purpose is to cultivate communication
skills among students, right?
Ms. Kashiwabara.
That's right.
Pair-work also fosters cooperativeness
and encourages
an independent learning attitude.
That's right.
You all haven't looked me
in the eyes today,
and I get the sense I'm being ignored.
You're just imagining it.
We aren't doing that at all.
They were definitely ignoring me,
those kids!
Onicchi, wait!
What? Huh?
Huh?
Thanks, the both of you.
For what?
You two were the only ones
to look me in the eyes.
This is about that.
The other day, we got this post.
LET'S ACT LIKE ONIZUKA DOESN'T EXIST
Who would do such a thing?
Who knows.
Could it be…
It's like this class has
a hidden mastermind, like on TV…
-No, that's a bit…
-I don't think so.
There's no bullying or anything.
If anything, they all just don't want
their own world to be disturbed.
Yeah, exactly.
Then, why does everyone act
in perfect unison when they see this?
"Let's act like Onizuka doesn't exist."
Well, you see…
It's kind of persuasive.
Ever since our previous homeroom teacher,
someone has been making these posts.
In this case, when we thought,
"Onicchi is barging in here,
bossing us around, he's annoying,"
they made a perfectly timed comment.
Yeah, exactly.
It's like how, with social media,
malicious posts can spread like wildfire.
Those who post things like this
enjoy seeing people influenced by them.
Then, what do you think I should do?
Just do what you want, Mr. Onizuka.
There you go saying that again!
Miss, do you have a moment?
What's wrong? Kotone.
I need to talk to you, Ms. Kashiwabara.
Tell me instead.
I'll listen to anything you have to say.
I'm sorry.
It's a delicate matter,
I can't tell a tactless man like you.
Okay.
Ms. Koizumi.
What do you think
this "delicate matter" is?
Who knows. It may be an issue
that she can only tell a woman.
It's so troublesome, isn't it?
Male teachers can't say anything careless.
Lately, even when I talk to my wife
and daughter, I worry about compliance.
No.
If you have something to say,
just say it clearly.
Like, "Goodbye, compliance."
You can't do that!
Don't just pop up out of nowhere!
In this era, that sort of thing
doesn't fly anymore.
Stop acting like
the old days were so great
and update yourself
to fit the times already.
If we have love
and conviction on our side…
Those things are invisible
and can't be proven, so the students
and parents won't understand.
Besides, when someone like you
breaks the rules and causes problems,
it troubles the other teachers too.
Is that so?
My mission as the vice-principal
is to make sure
all the teachers at our school
can do their jobs a little bit easier.
For that purpose,
I am prepared to become a shield
to protect the children here,
and I'm sure all of you
understand my efforts.
Is that the case?
What did Kotone say?
Seems she wants to change her partner.
What?
Oh…
Her partner is Ayumu Yoshida?
What exactly doesn't she like about him?
Apparently,
he's been glaring at her lately,
and it's creeping her out.
Mr. Ayumu?
Do you have a moment?
What is it?
It's just…
Kotone said she feels
like you're always glaring at her.
What? What's that about?
I'm not doing that.
Maybe she's scared of that look.
Though I'm sure you're being serious.
Serious?
You like Kotone, don't you?
I don't want you to misunderstand,
it's not like I care about her.
She just happens to be
in my line of sight.
Okay! Then I'll go tell her that.
"He doesn't have feelings for you.
Don't be stupid and misunderstand…"
Hey!
"Hey"?
What is it?
No, but…
You do like her, right?
Then, why don't you just tell her?
There's no way it'll go smoothly.
Why?
Because I have nothing going for me.
I'm not cool like Soma.
I'm not smart like Itsuki.
I'm bad at sports too,
so I'm envious of Hiroto.
What are you saying? I'm sure
you have plenty of good qualities.
For example?
Well…
That would be…
You eat your food
without leaving leftovers,
and you do the cleaning properly.
You're never late, either.
Anyone can do that.
No, don't give up, keep trying.
I'll help you with anything.
Then, can you make Kotone like me?
Hang on, how would I do that?
Think about that yourself.
There must be plenty of ways.
Like subtly making her think, "Good things
will happen if I go out with him."
But don't tell her I like her.
I don't want to be hated.
What a difficult request…
There she is.
This book, please.
9 - LITERATURE
Ms. Kotone Wakatsuki.
Please return the book by this date.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Ms. Kotone, do you have a moment?
It's about Ayumu.
What about him?
He isn't glaring at you.
It's just that when he gets serious,
his face looks like that.
Serious?
No, it's… Well, you know…
I think he might like you.
What?
Why don't you try going out with him?
He may look like that, but you can feel
he hides a burning passion.
They say you can't judge
a book by its cover, no?
I just said something
pretty good, didn't I?
Please be quiet.
Oh, sorry.
-Excuse me.
-Wait a minute! Hold up!
Please tell him
I have no intention of dating anyone.
Kotone.
I mean romance is not worth it at all,
and it's troublesome!
Getting anxious when a text
doesn't get a reply…
Or getting jealous when the person
you like talks to someone else…
If I'm going to waste energy like that,
reading a book is way better.
When you put it like that…
So, did you tell Ayumu Yoshida?
Well, I couldn't just lie to him.
And then?
I'm done for.
Hey, don't give up so easily.
What?
What are you talking about?
It's your fault.
Why did you go and say that I like her?
I only said that you might like her.
Enough already.
Please tell her
she won't have to see me again
until graduation, so rest easy.
Ayumu.
Does this mean he's finally over it?
No.
Leaving it like this
just leaves a bad taste.
If he's going to get rejected, I think
it's best he expresses his feelings first.
And Kotone shouldn't just say
she doesn't want to date anyone.
I can understand her feelings, though.
What?
Huh?
Why is that?
I also find romance to be a hassle,
so if I ever want to date,
I'll just use an app.
What? Isn't that dangerous?
Those are dating sites, right?
It's very like you
to have those prejudices,
but even the government
promotes those apps nowadays.
You can see the users'
hobbies and interests,
so you can easily choose your type.
No, but leaving human relationships,
the most important thing to us,
up to an AI to decide,
isn't that a bit off?
Right, Ms. Koizumi?
I married a man I chose myself.
And I bitterly regret it.
Once my child grows up,
I plan to use an app.
Huh? Ms. Koizumi, are you a single mother?
Is there a problem?
Of course not.
What about you, Mr. Abe?
I have no interest in marriage
in the first place.
What?
Mr. Abe, have you never
dated anyone before?
Is it necessary to answer that?
Not at all.
Hey.
Mr. Murayama, I'm sure
you don't know much about those "apps"?
My wife and daughter tell me…
"If you divorce,
there are apps for seniors.
You can find a partner there."
Mr. Murayama, are you getting divorced?
No, it's just a joke.
What about you, Mr. Onizuka?
For me…
It was like a spark when we met.
We're bound by destiny,
so even now we're lovey-dovey.
Mr. Onizuka!
Your wife sent me an email,
for old times' sake.
What?
It's heartwarming. You don't mind
if I let everyone hear it, right?
Hey.
"Mr. Nakamaru,
is my husband doing his job properly?
If he is causing trouble like he used to,
please feel free to give him an earful.
He has been getting quite cocky lately."
Wow, what a lovely wife you have!
Why did she marry a man like you?
I bet your wife loves you lots, huh?
-Oh!
-What?
It's best not to say that.
What?
His wife just divorced him last year.
His second divorce.
What, no way!
What about you, Principal?
I've been married three times,
so even now child support
and alimony are a struggle for me.
Sounds tough.
I wasn't looking at her.
Don't push yourself.
I'm not.
I don't care about her anymore anyway.
Hey.
Can I ask you one thing?
What?
What do you like about Kotone?
She's always reading a book.
It's nice, huh?
There's that too, but…
But?
We ran into each other
at the shopping district once before.
Even though she was meeting
my mother for the first time…
Nice to meet you.
I was so shocked, I couldn't say anything.
I thought, "Wow, she's really mature."
Even the store clerks and the librarian,
she never fails to greet them.
I don't think there are many people
our age who can do that.
What?
Those feelings of yours…
You should share them.
What?
Kotone will surely be happy.
If she knows
that you think of her that way.
Do you think so?
All right. Operation Confession is a go!
What?
What's with that lame name?
Before we start the strategy meeting,
let me introduce today's special lecturer.
What?
Mr. Ryunosuke Miyazawa.
Hello.
I feel like I've seen him before.
But who is he?
He's someone dispatched
from the company that runs our school.
Ryunosuke.
By the way, he's a former student of mine.
Really?
No way! And he still grew up
to be a proper adult?
Shut up.
But why is he here?
Ryunosuke has made
countless women cry in the past.
If you listen to his advice,
success is guaranteed!
Please don't spread
misinformation, Mr. Onizuka.
Well then, any strategies?
Maybe a bike ride to the sea?
Or maybe we change your hairstyle?
Or a present? Maybe even a ring?
I figured that's how
you flirted with women…
Bet you failed every single time.
Shut up.
Then how did you do it, Ryunosuke?
I've never confessed to anyone myself.
Damn! You make me mad.
Master, please teach me how to be popular.
Hey, this isn't about you.
Yeah, right now it's about Ayumu.
We have to think of something.
If I recall, she said
his face was scary, right?
So for now, you need to look
more cheerful.
Maybe show that you have
a playful side too?
How?
Let's see, for example…
Uh…
What about DAIGO-speak?
Oh, that might be pretty good.
What's that?
You don't know about it?
Those acronyms that DAIGO,
the celebrity, often uses.
I think I saw him in a video.
He abbreviates things, right?
For example, KDO.
"Kotone Do you want to go Out?"
It's easier than saying it as is, right?
I see!
He's coming back.
How did it go?
I thought about it a lot,
and I said KAU.
KAU?
"Kotone, Are you Up for hanging out?"
Oh, that's good!
How did she respond?
GM.
What?
GM? Oh!
"Get away from Me."
I knew it, a love letter is the way to go!
But what should I write?
When I want to keep a conversation
going over messaging or text,
I try to ask questions that grab
the other person's interest.
For example?
One I often use is,
"If a genie in a lamp
granted you three wishes,
what would you wish for?"
I don't have any.
What?
Genies don't exist, and if you have
a wish, you have to work to realize it.
I see, you're absolutely right.
But right now, I might have one.
Oh, what is it?
For you to stop interrupting my reading.
Bye!
Bye.
STRATEGY MEETING 3
What are we going to do now, Ryunosuke?
Huh? Oh, right.
Are you actually popular with girls?
Listen, I've never
had to confess to anyone!
Oh!
If Kotone likes books,
there's always that move.
The one you see on TV.
I don't watch TV shows. What do you mean?
Like,
as a girl reaches out to take a book,
someone else's hand touches hers.
In that moment, for some reason,
her heart skips a beat.
When she looks,
there is a wonderful guy
reaching for the same book,
"Do you like this novel?"
"I like it too," and like that,
the two of them instantly fall in love.
What are you doing?
What a coincidence.
Do you like this book?
So do I.
Cyrano de Bergerac is great, isn't it?
The main character's feelings
really tug at your heartstrings.
You can really empathize with him.
The fact that you chose this book,
could it be destiny?
So,
if you'd like, next time,
would you… with me?
Excuse me!
CLASS 1-B
Why did you run away?
I mean…
The more I talked,
the more put off by me she seemed.
Also, why are you so polite around Kotone?
You can't blame me,
we're classmates but we've barely spoken.
Don't say such pathetic things.
Act more like a man!
Women…
They prefer a guy who makes them think,
"What's up with him? He's the worst.
But I'm curious, my heart is pounding."
Rather than a guy who is just "nice."
-Is that how it is, Master?
-I think it depends on the person.
I'm just going to give up.
Don't say that.
Ms. Kashiwabara,
do you have any good ideas?
Personally, I think you'd be
better off consulting an AI.
Right, that's an option.
No, you've worked so hard to get this far.
Ayumu, now that it's come to this,
you just have to share
your feelings with her directly.
Right, don't you have
a dream or something?
What?
Since ancient times, men have always
talked about their dreams
to the women they love.
What? Is that true?
I've never done that myself.
Ayumu.
Don't you have a dream?
It's not that I don't have one, but…
Oh, I got it. A lawyer or a doctor.
You like listening to music, maybe a band?
Nowadays, kids also want to be
a pro gamer or a YouTuber!
I never had the courage
to tell anyone before.
You won't laugh, right?
No way I would.
Right?
The UN Secretary-General.
Wait, why?
I want to protect the Earth.
Sorry, what do you mean?
I mean, I want to reform the current UN,
abolish the permanent membership system,
eliminate war from the world,
and make countries all over the world
fight hard against global warming.
Otherwise, if things stay the way
they are, humanity will go extinct.
I knew it. You think it's dumb.
You're pretty
amazing.
What?
When I was a high school freshman,
I never thought about
anything so high-level,
so I think this is
something special about you!
Right, Ms. Kashiwabara?
Galileo was also mocked
by those around him at first,
but he stuck to his convictions and made
a huge contribution to humanity.
When I first met my wife,
she didn't see me as an option,
but I didn't give up and swore to love
only her, and we got married.
But she's left you right now, right?
Well, on TV, heroes have
to go through… a crisis, right?
Anyway, never mind about me.
Ayumu.
The only thing you need…
is courage.
That's her room.
Hey, how do you even know that?
When going home, I often
take the long way to pass by here.
Wait, that's just stalking.
Don't say that right now.
All right, everyone.
Stand by… start! Here we go!
-Hurry up!
-Hey, what are you doing?
Making it rain, what else?
Why?
It makes things more exciting!
When Kotone sees you drenched to the bone,
earnestly pleading your love,
she will be moved.
CYRANO DE BERGERAC
Ms. Kotone Wakatsuki!
Can you hear me?
No.
Kotone, can you hear me?
Wait, what are you doing?
I have a dream.
To one day become
the UN Secretary-General.
I want to change the world.
I want to create a world that does not
tolerate populism or discrimination.
A world where people don't yearn
for narrow-minded nationalism,
and instead atone
for the foolish, bloody history
that we humans have created so far!
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Well…
I mean…
Hey!
-What I mean is…
-Now's the time! Go!
Yes!
-Now!
-Okay!
Cyrano de Bergerac
was ultimately never united
with his beloved Roxane,
but even so, without losing heart,
he said two lines, which I love!
The first one is,
"To sing,
to dream, to laugh,
to walk, to be alone, be free…"
He actually read the book!
Nice one, Ayumu!
The other one
is the line Cyrano says
to Roxane at the very end.
"There's one thing I will take with me
as I leave this world, and that is…"
"My panache."
Please!
Kotone!
What?
Huh?
It's you, Onicchi! What are you doing?
Oh! This is just like that time!
When Kikuchi didn't come to school,
we made it rain!
How nostalgic! Whoa! Watch out!
-Sorry!
-You idiot.
-Onicchi, you okay?
-You!
Stop it!
-It's so cold!
-Stop it!
Don't spray me!
Watch out! Hey!
Don't ever speak to me again!
STAFF ROOM
Onizuka, as usual,
what on earth were you thinking?
The Principal has been apologizing
to Kotone Wakatsuki's mother
for a while now.
I apologized to her yesterday too.
And that's not all.
Look at this.
Because of you, Ayumu Yoshida
is getting bashed online too.
"His dream is to be Secretary-General?"
"He can't do it, that damn stalker."
Never mind me, but they
can't say such things to Ayumu!
I'll find who wrote this
and teach them a lesson!
Teach them a lesson?
I told you!
If you do that,
it will make the problem bigger,
and it will just cause trouble for us!
Why haven't you gotten it
through your head yet?
Everything you say and do
is problematic in this era!
Ryunosuke has made
countless women cry in the past.
Ms. Koizumi, are you a single mother?
Mr. Abe, have you never
dated anyone before?
No way, are all of those off-limits?
It's problematic for a teacher
to meddle in student romances!
You understand now, right?
Don't do unnecessary things anymore!
I've told him so many times…
Ms. Kashiwabara, do you also agree
with what the vice-principal said?
I don't think in this era, someone
like you can keep being a teacher.
Even so, I think it's amazing
that you keep trying.
Is that a compliment?
Or are you insulting me?
I'm just interested to see
what you'll do next.
Oh, okay.
Good morning.
About Mr. Ayumu…
I just, you know, wanted to support him,
and I would have done the same thing
for anyone in this class.
Because, you know,
I want everyone to enjoy their youth.
All right, I get it.
If you all want to pretend
I don't exist, go ahead and try.
But, Ayumu truly likes Kotone.
He just summoned the courage
to convey his massive dream.
I won't forgive anyone who makes fun
of his feelings and hurts him.
I didn't write those posts.
But everyone was asking me,
so I talked about it a little.
Besides, it has only been
two months since we met.
What does he actually know about me?
We haven't even talked much.
When someone likes me
just because of looks,
it's just a pain.
He didn't like you
just because of your looks.
What?
He respects the fact
that you greet adults properly
and that you're kind to everyone.
He truly admires that about you.
That's why
he fell in love with you, Kotone.
If there's anyone here
who wrote those posts online,
know that he gathered his courage
and expressed his feelings,
so don't dismiss him
and judge him by his cover!
He…
isn't a stalker or a fool.
The reason he confessed his love
was because he wanted
to make the person he loves happy!
He held that dream
because he wants
to save everyone in the world!
What on earth is wrong with that?
Calm down, Mr. Onizuka.
Yes?
I'm Onizuka, Ayumu's homeroom teacher.
Is your son home?
What?
Ayumu hasn't come home from school yet.
SUMMER LESSONS
UP YOUR GRADES AND MOTIVATION!
Ms. Ayano.
Have you seen Ayumu?
No, did something happen?
It looks like he lied to his parents today
about going to school.
I see.
Huh?
Oh!
Soma! What are you doing here?
What's with you? You look so panicked.
Ayumu is missing.
Let me know if you spot him.
-Oh.
-What?
I saw him a while ago.
What?
Ayumu?
Hey!
Ayumu, stop! Don't do anything stupid!
What are you doing?
What about you?
I dropped my earphone,
I was looking for it.
What?
Damn it.
I thought you were going to die.
You skipped school,
and didn't tell your parents.
Hey.
I was planning on going back tomorrow.
And besides, I can't afford to die.
Why?
Because…
If I died, Kotone would be hurt, right?
For her sake too,
I think I have to be my usual self.
So I thought I'd just spend today
crying my eyes out all by myself.
Ayumu.
You really are amazing.
What?
Don't ever change
that part about yourself.
And your dream of becoming
Secretary-General.
Oh, I gave up on that.
Why?
I figured it's better to be
a bit more realistic.
What?
When I looked at the ranking
of jobs high schoolers want to have,
customer service ranking first
or sales ranking fifth seem better to me.
What's up with that?
I know you're kind to people,
and I know you think things through.
But why are you so hard on yourself?
Why aren't you
expecting more from yourself?
Times like these,
you shouldn't be crying by yourself.
You just have to go wild and blow it off.
Isn't there something?
Something you
usually do to relieve stress.
Do I have something?
Yeah.
Onicchi, sorry we're late!
All right, let's have fun today!
Yeah!
Four people!
I'm terribly sorry.
We're currently full,
so it's a two-hour wait.
-Really?
-What?
Can't you do something about it, please?
It's a real drag.
Today is a party to cheer
this guy up, so please.
I am terribly sorry.
The heck you mean, "real drag"?
Look at that.
-Oh, what?
-Hey!
Oh!
She ran away!
She's running away!
Ms. Kashiwabara! What are you doing?
Please open up!
Oh! Ms. Kashiwabara, you're by yourself?
A solo customer!
She's a solo customer!
I just come here by myself sometimes.
I can eat food and do some work here.
Could it be you got your heart broken?
Really?
Wow. Nothing but breakup songs
in the history.
That's because I've never been
heartbroken, so I was doing research.
Oh, how annoying!
Who is it?
What?
I'll tell you!
I'll tell you, Ayumu Yoshida!
Hang in there! Can you hear me?
Hang in there!
I got rejected.
It was my first love.
I really loved her.
Heartbreak…
It hurts…
this much?
Mr. Onizuka.
Ayumu,
today,
you felt a feeling
you didn't know until yesterday.
There's a word for that.
What is it?
Well, people call it…
Right, Ms. Kashiwabara?
Growth?
Yes, exactly.
You are
growing right now.
Hey.
Want to take a BeReal?
Oh, sounds good! Wait, what is that?
Come on over.
Okay, let's go.
All right, cheese!
Please let me say just two things.
What is it?
First,
please don't get sick.
It's going to get hotter from now on,
so please watch out for heatstroke.
And the other thing?
Find someone nice.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it!
All right, everyone to your seats.
Now that Ayumu is here,
our class is a perfect number.
-Mr. Onizuka.
-Yes?
What's up?
Please make my nickname
"Secretary-General."
Understood. Secretary-General.
All right, let's start homeroom!
YOUR STUDIES
ONIZUKA NEEDS TO BE PUNISHED SOON
I wish he'd disappear soon.
What did you do now?
-If you can't, you're fired!
-It's been real.
-What?
She left a note saying
she's running away, now she's gone.
Why don't you try finding
your own way of doing things?
Your classes are famous
for being boring, Mr. Murayama.
Why don't you try doing something new?
Isn't that a bit too harsh?
I'm sure this time,
even your company will understand!
Make my family laugh.
Happy bday.
Subtitle translation by: Nix S.